Every heart has an awakening. Every soul needs a song.
Hounddog is a drama, music film directed by Deborah Kampmeier.
A drama set in the American South, where a precocious, troubled girl finds
a safe haven in the music and movement of Elvis Presley.
Lewellen, played by Dakota Fanning.
Boy 3, played by Oliver Clayton-Luce.
Grasshopper, played by Isabelle Fuhrman.
Buddy, played by Cody Hanford.
Grammie, played by Piper Laurie.
Daddy, played by David Morse.
Hounddog is a 2007
American coming-of-age drama film written,
directed, and produced by Deborah Kampmeier.
The film stars Dakota Fanning, Piper Laurie, David Morse, Robin
Wright Penn, and Isabelle Fuhrman in her film debut.
Filmed near Wilmington, North Carolina and set in 1956 Alabama, the film follows a troubled
girl who finds solace from an abusive life through the music of Elvis Presley.
Hounddog premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 22, 2007, where it was nominated for the
Grand Jury Prize, and was given a limited theatrical release on September 19, 2008.
Although Fanning was praised for her performance, the film was panned by critics due to a
controversial rape scene that was filmed when Fanning was only twelve years old.
It was also a commercial failure, grossing $131,961, against
an estimated $4 million production budget.
The tone is emotional.